<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on My eight week challenge</title>
        <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on My eight week challenge</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Monday, Day 15</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-3/monday-day-15/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-3/monday-day-15/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Public Holiday class which was a bit of the usual torture.
Food Breakfast: Banana slices with peanut butter. Lunch: Beef burger meat with quinoa, cabbage, cucumber and beetroot. And a little piece of airfryed salmon. Afternoon snack: Toast with butter. Dinner: TBA </description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Public Holiday class which was a bit of the usual torture.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Banana slices with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Lunch: Beef burger meat with quinoa, cabbage, cucumber and beetroot. And a little piece of airfryed salmon.</li>
<li>Afternoon snack: Toast with butter.</li>
<li>Dinner: TBA</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Sunday, Day 14</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/sunday-day-14/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/sunday-day-14/</guid>
            <description>Training Today was the Prana 2.8km Community run. I managed to get it done in a time of 18:29 which is a lot slower than my target of 15 minutes but was expected given my current fitness level.
Food </description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today was the Prana 2.8km Community run. I managed to get it done in a time of 18:29 which is a lot slower than my target of 15 minutes but was expected given my current fitness level.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Saturday, Day 13</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/saturday-day-13/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/saturday-day-13/</guid>
            <description>Training I did a HIIT class at 8:15. There were three pods (sets) worth of exercises and a corner run after each set. I think I did ok. I really tried to push myself on the corner runs so I can improve my time for the 2.8k run.
Food I ate:
Breakfast: Egg-ricotta and butter on toast. Lunch: Beef strips, broccoli, cabbage, avocado, cucumber and quinoa. Dinner: Cajun-spiced chicken breast, cabbage, celery and soba noodles.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I did a HIIT class at 8:15. There were three pods (sets) worth of exercises and a corner run after each set. I think I did ok. I really tried to push myself on the corner runs so I can improve my time for the 2.8k run.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>I ate:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Egg-ricotta and butter on toast.</li>
<li>Lunch: Beef strips, broccoli, cabbage, avocado, cucumber and quinoa.</li>
<li>Dinner: Cajun-spiced chicken breast, cabbage, celery and soba noodles.</li>
<li>Post-dinner snack: Chickpea nutella with strawberries.</li>
</ul>
<p>As for tracking on the MyFitnessPal app, I smashed my protein target today and just fell short of my fiber target. I also didn&rsquo;t hit my carb or fat intake today so something to think about for next week.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Friday, Day 12</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/friday-day-12/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/friday-day-12/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did a kickboxing session in the morning and it was a spicy one. Still a bit sore from Lift on Wednesday and yesterday&amp;rsquo;s core finisher but got the job done again.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few highlights:
There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem to support it. Though it isn&amp;rsquo;t really training, I walked for an hour today too.
Food Here&amp;rsquo;s what I ate today:</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did a kickboxing session in the morning and it was a spicy one. Still a bit sore from Lift on Wednesday and yesterday&rsquo;s core finisher but got the job done again.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a few highlights:</p>
<video class="video-shortcode" preload="" controls>
    <source src="/videos/week-2/friday/week-2-friday-kickboxing.mp4" type="video/mp4">
    There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem
    to support it.
</video>

<p>Though it isn&rsquo;t really training, I walked for an hour today too.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Pre-workout snack: Half a banana cut up with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Post-workout snack: Black bean cake.</li>
<li>Lunch: Chicken, cottage cheese, spinach, soba noodles and some cucumber.</li>
<li>Dessert: Yoghurt and blueberries.</li>
<li>Mid-afternoon snack: Soba noodles with chilli oil and soy sauce.</li>
<li>Dinner: Grass-fed beef strips with broccoli and green beans.</li>
<li>Post-dinner snack: Some soba noodles with avocado.</li>
<li>Post-dinner drink: A glass of carrot juice.</li>
</ul>
<p>I hit my protein and fiber targets on the MyFitnessPal app which is good. According to the app, I still have 679 calories to spend but I&rsquo;m not particularly hungry so it&rsquo;s time to call it a day.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thursday, Day 11</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/thursday-day-11/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/thursday-day-11/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Power class in the afternoon. It was a tough one again - 30X3X4 second movements plus 30 seconds of rest after a set of three movements. I&amp;rsquo;m feeling the burn after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Lift class, so skiiing was especially difficult. But I got it done - another session done and dusted.
Food Today, I ate:
Breakfast: Scrambled egg-ricotta on toast. Except I used olive oil instead of butter so it didn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Power class in the afternoon. It was a tough one again - 30X3X4 second movements plus 30 seconds of rest after a set of three movements. I&rsquo;m feeling the burn after yesterday&rsquo;s Lift class, so skiiing was especially difficult. But I got it done - another session done and dusted.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Today, I ate:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Scrambled egg-ricotta on toast. Except I used olive oil instead of butter so it didn&rsquo;t taste as good.</li>
<li>Breakfast dessert: Black bean cake.</li>
<li>Lunch: Mince, capsicum, mushroom and Vetta high-fibre spaghetti. A few chickpeas and some salmon sashimi.</li>
<li>Pre-workout snack: Half a banana sliced up with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Dinner: Chicken breast pieces with a ricotta-spinach sauce. Cucumber and celery was also added to up my vegetable intake. Plus some avocado for healthy fat.</li>
<li>After dinner: A bowl of soba noodles with chilli oil and soy sauce.</li>
</ul>
<p>According to this app I&rsquo;m using - MyFitnessPal - I&rsquo;ve met my protein intake but fallen short on carbs and fats. I think I need to probably up my fruit and veg intake a bit.</p>
<p>Anyway, here&rsquo;s a photo gallery of what I ate today.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wednesday, Day 10</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/wednesday-day-10/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/wednesday-day-10/</guid>
            <description>Training I did Speed and Lift today.
Speed was a classic cardio session with bike, skiing, rowing, ladder work and a corner run to boot.
Lift was 100% upper body strength exercises.
Lift class: I&amp;rsquo;m working hard in the background again&amp;hellip; Food I ate a lot today, as the following list shows:
Breakfast: Silken tofu-banana icecream from the Fitchef cookbook. It was delicious! Lunch: Chicken, ricotta and spinach sauce with Vetta high-fibre spaghetti and salad.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I did Speed and Lift today.</p>
<p>Speed was a classic cardio session with bike, skiing, rowing, ladder work and a corner run to boot.</p>
<p>Lift was 100% upper body strength exercises.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-2/wednesday/lift-class.jpg" alt="Lift class"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Lift class: I&rsquo;m working hard in the background again&hellip;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>I ate a lot today, as the following list shows:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Silken tofu-banana icecream from the <a href="https://payhip.com/b/VHzcn?fbclid=PAAaZW9y1GzuvqT5BHCzRMExJliGxX1xLI1CSQqwOttVhwXzkE4KZph6bE9jU">Fitchef cookbook</a>. It was delicious!</li>
<li>Lunch: Chicken, ricotta and spinach sauce with Vetta high-fibre spaghetti and salad.</li>
<li>Dinner: Beef burger meat, mince, capsicum and mushroom with soba noodles.</li>
<li>Snack:
<ul>
<li>Baked potato.</li>
<li>Half a banana cut into slices with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Yoghurt with blueberries.</li>
<li>Black bean cake.</li>
<li>A bowl of Vetta spaghetti with chilli oil and soy sauce.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tuesday, Day 9</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/tuesday-day-9/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/tuesday-day-9/</guid>
            <description>Training Today was kickboxing day. Without getting repetitive, it was hard, but I got through the session. No cramping today as I took care of my water intake.
Also, as part of the team challenge, I did 40 (2X10 on my toes, 2X10 on my knees) push ups today, meaning I have 100 left to go for the rest of the week.
Food Today was a tough day as I was busy at work and couldn&amp;rsquo;t snack as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today was kickboxing day. Without getting repetitive, it was hard, but I got through the session. No cramping today as I took care of my water intake.</p>
<p>Also, as part of the team challenge, I did 40 (2X10 on my toes, 2X10 on my knees) push ups today, meaning I have 100 left to go for the rest of the week.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Today was a tough day as I was busy at work and couldn&rsquo;t snack as much as I&rsquo;d like. Anyway, this is what I ate:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Overnight oats with peanut butter and berries (only finished half).</li>
<li>Lunch: Beef burger meat with some avocado salad and soba noodles mixed with chilli oil and soy sauce.</li>
<li>Dinner: Mince, capsicum, mushroom and Vetta high-fibre spaghetti with chilli oil and soy sauce. I had another serving of the same meal, this time with soba noodles</li>
<li>Snack: A bowl of soba noodles with chilli oil and soy sauce.</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Monday, Day 8</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/monday-day-8/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/monday-day-8/</guid>
            <description>Training Today was a solid session of training to begin week 2 of the eight-week challenge. I did the Speed class followed by Lift. Sometimes, Speed is a fairly cardio heavy class but today there was a good balance between weights, cardio and whatever box jumping is haha. I struggled a bit in Lift today - was cramping in my calf. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve been drinking enough water so that&amp;rsquo;s something I need to work on.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today was a solid session of training to begin week 2 of the eight-week challenge. I did the Speed class followed by Lift. Sometimes, Speed is a fairly cardio heavy class but today there was a good balance between weights, cardio and whatever box jumping is haha. I struggled a bit in Lift today - was cramping in my calf. I don&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;ve been drinking enough water so that&rsquo;s something I need to work on.</p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>So this is what I had today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Overnight oats (only finished half of it though).</li>
<li>Lunch: My famous mince capsicum and mushroom dish with Vetta high-fibre spaghetti and a side of salmon sashimi.</li>
<li>Snack: A banana sliced up with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Dinner: My celery, carrot and cucumber salad from last night with the chicken-ricotta-spinach thing I made on Saturday. Topped off with some extra soba noodles. Note: I ate more than what the photo suggests. I may have had extra chicken as I was still hungry.</li>
<li>Snack: Some baked potato.</li>
</ul>
<p>I&rsquo;ve lost around a kilo and a half since the weigh in pre-challenge so I&rsquo;m pretty happy with my efforts. Hopefully, I can keep it up.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Sunday, Day 7</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/sunday-day-7/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/sunday-day-7/</guid>
            <description>Training I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreading today&amp;rsquo;s 2.8km community run all week. But I got it done without stopping once, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of myself. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit annoyed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t time myself - I set up Strava on my new phone and everything - but forgot to start the timer. It&amp;rsquo;s all good though, I&amp;rsquo;ll time myself next week.
Straight after the community run Food Today was basically all about using up what&amp;rsquo;s in the fridge.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been dreading today&rsquo;s 2.8km community run all week. But I got it done without stopping once, so I&rsquo;m pretty proud of myself. I&rsquo;m a bit annoyed that I didn&rsquo;t time myself - I set up Strava on my new phone and everything - but forgot to start the timer. It&rsquo;s all good though, I&rsquo;ll time myself next week.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/sunday/community-run.jpg" alt="After the community run"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Straight after the community run</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Today was basically all about using up what&rsquo;s in the fridge. So mind me if the combinations get a bit weird.</p>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Had a medium banana sliced up with peanut butter pre run and then the <a href="../saturday-day-6">chickpea-hazelnut mousse I made yesterday</a> with some strawberries after the run.</li>
<li>Lunch: Beef burger meat, chicken breast and ricotta-spinach spaghetti (<a href="../saturday-day-6">made yesterday</a> and some green beans)</li>
<li>Dinner: Lasagne with some chopped up cucumber, celery and carrot.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>Yopro yoghurt with some blueberries in the afternoon.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I couldn&rsquo;t help myself for dinner and about 10 minutes later had this massive extra serving of lasagne:</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/sunday/more-lasagne.jpg" alt="Extra slice of lasagne"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Extra slice of lasagne</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Saturday, Day 6</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/saturday-day-6/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/saturday-day-6/</guid>
            <description>Training I did Prana&amp;rsquo;s 8:15 HIIT class today. There was lots of bike work, a bit of weights, kettle bell work and a core finisher.
Saturday&amp;rsquo;s Power/HIIT class at Prana I went for a 40-minute walk in the evening too. It&amp;rsquo;s not training but I&amp;rsquo;m adding it here :).
Now I&amp;rsquo;m dreading tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s run.
Go back to Table of Contents
Meal prep for week 2 I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bit on tomorrow, so I&amp;rsquo;ve done some meal prep today.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I did Prana&rsquo;s 8:15 HIIT class today. There was lots of bike work, a bit of weights, kettle bell work and a core finisher.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/saturday/workout-hiit.jpg" alt="Saturday&amp;rsquo;s Power/HIIT class at Prana"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Saturday&rsquo;s Power/HIIT class at Prana</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I went for a 40-minute walk in the evening too. It&rsquo;s not training but I&rsquo;m adding it here :).</p>
<p>Now I&rsquo;m dreading tomorrow&rsquo;s run.</p>
<p><a href="saturday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="meal-prep-for-week-2">Meal prep for week 2</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;ve got a bit on tomorrow, so I&rsquo;ve done some meal prep today. I&rsquo;ve made about three lunches worth of chicken, ricotta sauce and spinach.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also made a delicious healthy nutella. I got the recipe from <a href="https://chocolatecoveredkatie.com/better-than-nutella/">chocolatecoveredkatie</a>, a healthy dessert blog. The only difference is I used cacao powder and I had a lot less hazelnuts.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/saturday/homemade-nutella.jpg" alt="Healthy nutella"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Healthy nutella</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="saturday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Half of the overnight oats made last night (<a href="https://feelgoodfoodie.net/recipe/overnight-oats/">recipe here</a> + protein powder) and beef burger meat. It&rsquo;s weird, but I saw the beef burger meat in the fridge and couldn&rsquo;t resist.</li>
<li>Lunch: Chicken breast pieces with a ricotta, pepita and flax seed sauce and spinach. Served with some high-fibre Vetta pasta from yesterday (not the high-protein version I thought it was). Based on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/Clyr-ooprNU/?igshid=NDk5N2NlZjQ=">this recipe</a> from Instagram.</li>
<li>Dinner: Cucumber, beetroot and soba noodle salad with a bit of leftover mince, capsicum and mushroom from the week.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>Half a banana sliced up with peanut butter.</li>
<li>Finished off the overnight oats in the afternoon.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>And a small confession. I may have had a little bit of this delicious lasagne made by my sister. Not exactly contributing to the cause, but was worth the calories :).</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/saturday/lasagne.jpg" alt="Homemade lasagna"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Homemade lasagna</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="saturday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Friday, Day 5</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/friday-day-5/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/friday-day-5/</guid>
            <description>Training I started off the day with a kickboxing session. It was hard work but also a bit of fun with some back spinning elbow strikes - it almost made me feel like a real martial artist haha.
Go back to Table of Contents
Win of the day So, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked out how to add an image carousel to my pages!!!! That means I now have an easy way to add images to each of my challenge-series posts.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I started off the day with a kickboxing session. It was hard work but also a bit of fun with some back spinning elbow strikes - it almost made me feel like a real martial artist haha.</p>
<p><a href="friday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="win-of-the-day">Win of the day</h2>
<p>So, I&rsquo;ve worked out how to add an image carousel to my pages!!!! That means I now have an easy way to add images to each of my challenge-series posts. I did use someone&rsquo;s else&rsquo;s script and tweaked it, but I&rsquo;m still so happy.</p>
<p><a href="friday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: My fave - Eggs and ricotta on toast.</li>
<li>Lunch: Lettuce, cherry tomato, beetroot and avocado salad with beef burger meat. And straight after, a small bowl of soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce.</li>
<li>Dinner: Tempeh bolognese with Vetta high-protein spaghetti and spinach. Inspo from <a href="https://theplantbasedschool.com/tempeh-bolognese/">this recipe</a> and a recipe from <a href="https://payhip.com/b/VHzcn?fbclid=PAAaZW9y1GzuvqT5BHCzRMExJliGxX1xLI1CSQqwOttVhwXzkE4KZph6bE9jU">Prana coach Darian&rsquo;s new cookbook</a>.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>Yoghurt with blueberries and one blackberry (there was only one left).</li>
<li>An oatmeal-banana-choc chip cookie made by the wonderful Lisa.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="friday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Thursday, Day 4</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</guid>
            <description>Training I did Power today and it was pretty tough. After a block run and a 5 minute warm up, we did 3 rounds of 10 minutes worth exercise - an upper body pod, a lower body pod and a kettle bell pod. Exercises included things like renegade rows, commandos, lunges and sleds. After completing 1 round of exercises at a pod, we had to do a right corner run and then repeat the round until the 10 minutes was over.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I did Power today and it was pretty tough. After a block run and a 5 minute warm up, we did 3 rounds of 10 minutes worth exercise - an upper body pod, a lower body pod and a kettle bell pod. Exercises included things like renegade rows, commandos, lunges and sleds. After completing 1 round of exercises at a pod, we had to do a right corner run and then repeat the round until the 10 minutes was over.
I&rsquo;m glad it&rsquo;s over haha but I feel like I got a lot out of today.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/thursday/power.png" alt="A Power/HIIT class at Prana"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">A Power/HIIT class at Prana</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="thursday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta yet again.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish repeated with some cauliflower from last nigh and a side of salmon sashimi.</li>
<li>Dinner: Cajun spiced chicken breast with asparagus. About 10 minutes later, I chowed down some soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>Half a banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>An oat milk mocha. Pretty sure that wasn&rsquo;t in the meal plan but oh well&hellip;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="thursday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wednesday, Day 3</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and Lift (50min) classes just like Monday, except that Lift was focussed entirely on upper body exercises.
Speed involved 50 calorie sprints and then some rest equal to the time you took to complete the 50 calories. We were meant to do three lots of sprints but I could only burn 130 calories so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit annoyed. My legs are still shot from the Lift class on Monday.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Speed (20min) and Lift (50min) classes just like Monday, except that Lift was focussed entirely on upper body exercises.</p>
<p>Speed involved 50 calorie sprints and then some rest equal to the time you took to complete the 50 calories. We were meant to do three lots of sprints but I could only burn 130 calories so I&rsquo;m a bit annoyed. My legs are still shot from the Lift class on Monday. But it gives me something to work on.</p>
<p>Lift was alright but I was so hungry after. I think I might have to consider upping my protein intake but I&rsquo;ll see where I&rsquo;m at later in the week and readjust.</p>
<p><a href="wednesday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta again. It&rsquo;s really good.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish again. Added some asparagus too.</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth again.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>Some YoPro high protein yoghurt with a few berries.</li>
<li>Some roasted cauliflower with peanut butter and olive oil.</li>
<li>A little piece of beef burger meat with some soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce as I was still hungry after Lift.</li>
<li>Some more soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce as I was still hungry after the burger.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I fear that I snacked too much today and ate too much peanut butter :(. Given that I&rsquo;ve packed the extra cauliflower tomorrow which has peanut butter, I might skip my beloved banana with peanut butter tomorrow and just have the banana.</p>
<p><a href="wednesday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tuesday, Day 2</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I had a kickboxing PT session (45min) with coach Darian at Prana. It&amp;rsquo;s hard work and sometimes I regret my life choices while I&amp;rsquo;m there, but once the session is over, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to these sessions for at least a year now, for at least two times a week and it&amp;rsquo;s really improved my fitness. I highly recommend you try kickboxing with Darian - he&amp;rsquo;s a hard task master but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a lot out of it.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I had a kickboxing PT session (45min) with coach Darian at Prana. It&rsquo;s hard work and sometimes I regret my life choices while I&rsquo;m there, but once the session is over, I&rsquo;m so glad I&rsquo;ve done it. I&rsquo;ve been going to these sessions for at least a year now, for at least two times a week and it&rsquo;s really improved my fitness. I highly recommend you try kickboxing with Darian - he&rsquo;s a hard task master but you&rsquo;ll get a lot out of it.</p>
<p><a href="tuesday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish again.</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth again with some asparagus.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice (pre-workout snack).</li>
<li>Some YoPro high protein yoghurt with a few blueberries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="tuesday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Monday, Day 1</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and lower body Lift (50min)n classes at Prana. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Speed is a cardio-based class with lots of bike work paired with either running or lifting medium weights. Lift is a strength-based class with a lot of heavy weights lifting. It was a tough one but I got it done.
I&amp;rsquo;m working hard (during Lift), I swear&amp;hellip; Go back to Table of Contents</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Speed (20min) and lower body Lift (50min)n classes at Prana. For those of you that don&rsquo;t know, Speed is a cardio-based class with lots of bike work paired with either running or lifting medium weights. Lift is a strength-based class with a lot of heavy weights lifting. It was a tough one but I got it done.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/week-1/monday/me-working-hard-lift.jpg" alt="Me working hard in a Lift class"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">I&rsquo;m working hard (during Lift), I swear&hellip;</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="monday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a summary of what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Overnight oats with peanut butter and mixed berries.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish I prepared yesterday.</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth and cauliflower.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice (pre-workout snack).</li>
<li>A glass of carrot juice (after dinner).</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>A little extra: I bought salmon sashimi today at work cos I was still hungry after lunch.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="monday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Pre Challenge Prep</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 08:23:37 +1030</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</guid>
            <description>Fitness testing On Saturday, I went down to Grange Jetty to complete some fitness testing prior to the eight week challenge. The fitness testing included:
1 minute of push ups. 1 minute of sit ups. A beach run from Grange Jetty to Henley Jetty and back. I was a bit worried about the run, as my aerobic capacity is not the greatest. But I got through it in a time of 28:42.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="fitness-testing">Fitness testing</h2>
<p>On Saturday, I went down to Grange Jetty to complete some fitness testing prior to the eight week challenge. The fitness testing included:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 minute of push ups.</li>
<li>1 minute of sit ups.</li>
<li>A beach run from Grange Jetty to Henley Jetty and back.</li>
</ul>
<p>I was a bit worried about the run, as my aerobic capacity is not the greatest. But I got through it in a time of 28:42.
I celebrated my run with an oat milk latte from Grange Jetty and am looking forward to improving my time over the eight weeks.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/grange-jetty-testing-coffee.jpg" alt="Mel, me and Lisa at Grange Jetty cafe"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Mel, me and Lisa enjoying a delicious oat milk coffee</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="body-scan">Body scan</h2>
<p>On Sunday, I went to Prana headquarters and got my measurements and body scan done. I&rsquo;ve come a long way (I&rsquo;ve put on 3kg of muscle since my previous scan with SA Body Analysis) but there&rsquo;s more work to be done. Here&rsquo;s to eight weeks of hard work!</p>
<h2 id="community-walk">Community walk</h2>
<p>Well, technically, it was meant to be a run. But I ended up walking as I was a bit sore from the day before. I&rsquo;m looking to improve my endurance so I am <strong>committing to running every week</strong>. Yes, you heard it here. From now on, no more excuses :).</p>
<p>After the walk, I had another delicious coffee at Willow Bend in Croydon.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/community-run-pre-challenge.jpg" alt="Some of the Prana crew after the community run/walk"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Some of the Prana crew after the community run/walk</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="meal-prep">Meal prep</h2>
<p>After the walk and a bit of lunch, I got straight onto prepping meals for the week.  This included:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushrooms</strong> with red rice and a dash of chilli infused oil.
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/lunch.jpg" alt="Lean mince, capsicum and mushrooms with chilli oil, cabbage pan-fried in turmeric and coconut and red rice"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Lean mince, capsicum and mushrooms with chilli oil, cabbage pan-fried in turmeric and coconut and red rice</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</li>
<li><strong>Overnight oats</strong> for Monday
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/breakfast-prep.jpg" alt="Overnight oats ready to be put in the fridge for tomorrow"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Overnight oats ready to be put in the fridge for tomorrow</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="fail-of-the-day">Fail of the day</h2>
<p>Full disclosure - I&rsquo;m not a great cook. I just throw things together or follow recipes I find and hope things work out. But sometimes, things don&rsquo;t work out&hellip;</p>
<p>So for a bit of fun, I thought I&rsquo;d include a section which acknowledges a &ldquo;fail&rdquo; of the day. I think it&rsquo;s important to learn from mistakes and try and have a laugh as well.</p>
<p>So here&rsquo;s what happened today. For some reason, I cooked the oats and it exploded in the microwave. Hopefully, it will taste OK tomorrow with a bit of peanut butter and fruit. But I&rsquo;ll definitely let you know.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
