<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on My eight week challenge</title>
        <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on My eight week challenge</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>Thursday, Day 4</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</guid>
            <description>Training I did Power today and it was pretty tough. After a block run and a 5 minute warm up, we did 3 rounds of 10 minutes worth exercise - an upper body pod, a lower body pod and a kettle bell pod. Exercises included things like renegade rows, commandos, lunges and sleds. After completing 1 round of exercises at a pod, we had to do a right corner run and then repeat the round until the 10 minutes was over.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>I did Power today and it was pretty tough. After a block run and a 5 minute warm up, we did 3 rounds of 10 minutes worth exercise - an upper body pod, a lower body pod and a kettle bell pod. Exercises included things like renegade rows, commandos, lunges and sleds. After completing 1 round of exercises at a pod, we had to do a right corner run and then repeat the round until the 10 minutes was over.
I&rsquo;m glad it&rsquo;s over haha but I feel like I got a lot out of today.</p>
<p><a href="thursday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta yet again.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish repeated with some cauliflower from last nigh and a side of salmon sashimi.</li>
<li>Dinner: Cajun spiced chicken breast with asparagus. About 10 minutes later, I chowed down some soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>Half a banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>An oat milk mocha. Pretty sure that wasn&rsquo;t in the meal plan but oh well&hellip;</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="thursday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Wednesday, Day 3</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and Lift (50min) classes just like Monday, except that Lift was focussed entirely on upper body exercises.
Speed involved 50 calorie sprints and then some rest equal to the time you took to complete the 50 calories. We were meant to do three lots of sprints but I could only burn 130 calories so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit annoyed. My legs are still shot from the Lift class on Monday.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Speed (20min) and Lift (50min) classes just like Monday, except that Lift was focussed entirely on upper body exercises.</p>
<p>Speed involved 50 calorie sprints and then some rest equal to the time you took to complete the 50 calories. We were meant to do three lots of sprints but I could only burn 130 calories so I&rsquo;m a bit annoyed. My legs are still shot from the Lift class on Monday. But it gives me something to work on.</p>
<p>Lift was alright but I was so hungry after. I think I might have to consider upping my protein intake but I&rsquo;ll see where I&rsquo;m at later in the week and readjust.</p>
<p><a href="wednesday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta again. It&rsquo;s really good.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish again. Added some asparagus too.</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth again.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>Some YoPro high protein yoghurt with a few blueberries.</li>
<li>Some roasted cauliflower with peanut butter and olive oil.</li>
<li>A little piece of beef burger meat with some soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce as I was still hungry after Lift.</li>
<li>Some more soba noodles with chilli-infused oil and soy sauce as I was still hungry after the burger.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I fear that I snacked too much today and ate too much peanut butter :(. Given that I&rsquo;ve packed the extra cauliflower tomorrow which has peanut butter, I might skip my beloved banana with peanut butter tomorrow and just have the banana.</p>
<p><a href="wednesday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tuesday, Day 2</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I had a kickboxing PT session (45min) with coach Darian at Prana. It&amp;rsquo;s hard work and sometimes I regret my life choices while I&amp;rsquo;m there, but once the session is over, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to these sessions for at least a year now, for at least two times a week and it&amp;rsquo;s really improved my fitness. I highly recommend you try kickboxing with Darian - he&amp;rsquo;s a hard task master but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a lot out of it.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I had a kickboxing PT session (45min) with coach Darian at Prana. It&rsquo;s hard work and sometimes I regret my life choices while I&rsquo;m there, but once the session is over, I&rsquo;m so glad I&rsquo;ve done it. I&rsquo;ve been going to these sessions for at least a year now, for at least two times a week and it&rsquo;s really improved my fitness. I highly recommend you try kickboxing with Darian - he&rsquo;s a hard task master but you&rsquo;ll get a lot out of it.</p>
<p><a href="tuesday.md#reference" style="margin:0;">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: One scrambled egg mixed with ricotta.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish again</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth again with some asparagus.</li>
<li>Snacks:
<ul>
<li>A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>Some YoPro high protein yoghurt with a few blueberries.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="tuesday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Monday, Day 1</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</guid>
            <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and lower body Lift (50min)n classes at Prana. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Speed is a cardio-based class with lots of bike work paired with either running or lifting medium weights. Lift is a strength-based class with a lot of heavy weights lifting.
Go back to Table of Contents
Food Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of what I ate today:
Breakfast: Overnight oats with peanut butter and mixed berries.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><span id="reference"></span></p>
<h2 id="training">Training</h2>
<p>Today, I did the Speed (20min) and lower body Lift (50min)n classes at Prana. For those of you that don&rsquo;t know, Speed is a cardio-based class with lots of bike work paired with either running or lifting medium weights. Lift is a strength-based class with a lot of heavy weights lifting.</p>
<p><a href="monday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
<h2 id="food">Food</h2>
<p>Here&rsquo;s a summary of what I ate today:</p>
<ul>
<li>Breakfast: Overnight oats with peanut butter and mixed berries.</li>
<li>Lunch: The lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushroom dish I prepared yesterday.</li>
<li>Dinner: Lamb shanks with broth.</li>
<li>Snacks: A full banana sliced up with peanut butter on each slice.</li>
<li>A little extra: I bought salmon sashimi today at work cos I was still hungry after lunch.</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="monday.md#reference">Go back to Table of Contents</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Pre Challenge Prep</title>
            <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 08:23:37 +1030</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</guid>
            <description>Fitness testing On Saturday, I went down to Grange Jetty to complete some fitness testing prior to the eight week challenge. The fitness testing included:
1 minute of push ups. 1 minute of sit ups. A beach run from Grange Jetty to Henley Jetty and back. I was a bit worried about the run, as my aerobic capacity is not the greatest. But I got through it in a time of 28:42.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="fitness-testing">Fitness testing</h2>
<p>On Saturday, I went down to Grange Jetty to complete some fitness testing prior to the eight week challenge. The fitness testing included:</p>
<ul>
<li>1 minute of push ups.</li>
<li>1 minute of sit ups.</li>
<li>A beach run from Grange Jetty to Henley Jetty and back.</li>
</ul>
<p>I was a bit worried about the run, as my aerobic capacity is not the greatest. But I got through it in a time of 28:42.
I celebrated my run with an oat milk latte from Grange Jetty and am looking forward to improving my time over the eight weeks.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/grange-jetty-testing-coffee.jpg" alt="Mel, me and Lisa at Grange Jetty cafe"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Mel, me and Lisa enjoying a delicious oat milk coffee</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="body-scan">Body scan</h2>
<p>On Sunday, I went to Prana headquarters and got my measurements and body scan done. I&rsquo;ve come a long way (I&rsquo;ve put on 3kg of muscle since my previous scan with SA Body Analysis) but there&rsquo;s more work to be done. Here&rsquo;s to eight weeks of hard work!</p>
<h2 id="community-walk">Community walk</h2>
<p>Well, technically, it was meant to be a run. But I ended up walking as I was a bit sore from the day before. I&rsquo;m looking to improve my endurance so I am <strong>committing to running every week</strong>. Yes, you heard it here. From now on, no more excuses :).</p>
<p>After the walk, I had another delicious coffee at Willow Bend in Croydon.</p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/community-run-pre-challenge.jpg" alt="Some of the Prana crew after the community run/walk"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Some of the Prana crew after the community run/walk</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2 id="meal-prep">Meal prep</h2>
<p>After the walk and a bit of lunch, I got straight onto prepping meals for the week.  This included:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Lean mince, cabbage, capsicum and mushrooms</strong> with red rice and a dash of chilli infused oil.
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/lunch.jpg" alt="Lean mince, capsicum and mushrooms with chilli oil, cabbage pan-fried in turmeric and coconut and red rice"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Lean mince, capsicum and mushrooms with chilli oil, cabbage pan-fried in turmeric and coconut and red rice</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</li>
<li><strong>Overnight oats</strong> for Monday
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:center"><img src="/images/pre-challenge/breakfast-prep.jpg" alt="Overnight oats ready to be put in the fridge for tomorrow"></th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:center">Overnight oats ready to be put in the fridge for tomorrow</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="fail-of-the-day">Fail of the day</h2>
<p>Full disclosure - I&rsquo;m not a great cook. I just throw things together or follow recipes I find and hope things work out. But sometimes, things don&rsquo;t work out&hellip;</p>
<p>So for a bit of fun, I thought I&rsquo;d include a section which acknowledges a &ldquo;fail&rdquo; of the day. I think it&rsquo;s important to learn from mistakes and try and have a laugh as well.</p>
<p>So here&rsquo;s what happened today. For some reason, I cooked the oats and it exploded in the microwave. Hopefully, it will taste OK tomorrow with a bit of peanut butter and fruit. But I&rsquo;ll definitely let you know.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
