<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My eight week challenge</title>
    <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My eight week challenge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Monday, Day 15</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-3/monday-day-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-3/monday-day-15/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I did the Public Holiday class which was a bit of the usual torture.
Food Breakfast: Banana slices with peanut butter. Lunch: Beef burger meat with quinoa, cabbage, cucumber and beetroot. And a little piece of airfryed salmon. Afternoon snack: Toast with butter. Dinner: TBA </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday, Day 14</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/sunday-day-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/sunday-day-14/</guid>
      <description>Training Today was the Prana 2.8km Community run. I managed to get it done in a time of 18:29 which is a lot slower than my target of 15 minutes but was expected given my current fitness level.
Food </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday, Day 13</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/saturday-day-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/saturday-day-13/</guid>
      <description>Training I did a HIIT class at 8:15. There were three pods (sets) worth of exercises and a corner run after each set. I think I did ok. I really tried to push myself on the corner runs so I can improve my time for the 2.8k run.
Saturday HIIT class Food I ate:
Breakfast: Egg-ricotta and butter on toast. Lunch: Beef strips, broccoli, cabbage, avocado, cucumber and quinoa. Dinner: Cajun-spiced chicken breast, cabbage, celery and soba noodles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friday, Day 12</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/friday-day-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/friday-day-12/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I did a kickboxing session in the morning and it was a spicy one. Still a bit sore from Lift on Wednesday and yesterday&amp;rsquo;s core finisher but got the job done again.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a few highlights:
There should have been a video here but your browser does not seem to support it. Though it isn&amp;rsquo;t really training, I walked for an hour today too.
Food Here&amp;rsquo;s what I ate today:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, Day 11</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/thursday-day-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/thursday-day-11/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I did the Power class in the afternoon. It was a tough one again - 30X3X4 second movements plus 30 seconds of rest after a set of three movements. I&amp;rsquo;m feeling the burn after yesterday&amp;rsquo;s Lift class, so skiiing was especially difficult. But I got it done - another session done and dusted.
Food Today, I ate:
Breakfast: Scrambled egg-ricotta on toast. Except I used olive oil instead of butter so it didn&amp;rsquo;t taste as good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday, Day 10</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/wednesday-day-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/wednesday-day-10/</guid>
      <description>Training I did Speed and Lift today.
Speed was a classic cardio session with bike, skiing, rowing, ladder work and a corner run to boot.
Lift was 100% upper body strength exercises.
Lift class: I&amp;rsquo;m working hard in the background again&amp;hellip; Food I ate a lot today, as the following list shows:
Breakfast: Silken tofu-banana icecream from the Fitchef cookbook. It was delicious! Lunch: Chicken, ricotta and spinach sauce with Vetta high-fibre spaghetti and salad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, Day 9</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/tuesday-day-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/tuesday-day-9/</guid>
      <description>Training Today was kickboxing day. Without getting repetitive, it was hard, but I got through the session. No cramping today as I took care of my water intake.
Also, as part of the team challenge, I did 40 (2X10 on my toes, 2X10 on my knees) push ups today, meaning I have 100 left to go for the rest of the week.
Food Today was a tough day as I was busy at work and couldn&amp;rsquo;t snack as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday, Day 8</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/monday-day-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-2/monday-day-8/</guid>
      <description>Training Today was a solid session of training to begin week 2 of the eight-week challenge. I did the Speed class followed by Lift. Sometimes, Speed is a fairly cardio heavy class but today there was a good balance between weights, cardio and whatever box jumping is haha. I struggled a bit in Lift today - was cramping in my calf. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve been drinking enough water so that&amp;rsquo;s something I need to work on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sunday, Day 7</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/sunday-day-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/sunday-day-7/</guid>
      <description>Training I&amp;rsquo;ve been dreading today&amp;rsquo;s 2.8km community run all week. But I got it done without stopping once, so I&amp;rsquo;m pretty proud of myself. I&amp;rsquo;m a bit annoyed that I didn&amp;rsquo;t time myself - I set up Strava on my new phone and everything - but forgot to start the timer. It&amp;rsquo;s all good though, I&amp;rsquo;ll time myself next week.
Straight after the community run Food Today was basically all about using up what&amp;rsquo;s in the fridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saturday, Day 6</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/saturday-day-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/saturday-day-6/</guid>
      <description>Training I did Prana&amp;rsquo;s 8:15 HIIT class today. There was lots of bike work, a bit of weights, kettle bell work and a core finisher.
Saturday&amp;rsquo;s Power/HIIT class at Prana I went for a 40-minute walk in the evening too. It&amp;rsquo;s not training but I&amp;rsquo;m adding it here :).
Now I&amp;rsquo;m dreading tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s run.
Go back to Table of Contents
Meal prep for week 2 I&amp;rsquo;ve got a bit on tomorrow, so I&amp;rsquo;ve done some meal prep today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
