<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My eight week challenge</title>
    <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/</link>
    <description>Recent content on My eight week challenge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thursday, Day 4</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/thursday-day-4/</guid>
      <description>Training I did Power today and it was pretty tough. After a block run and a 5 minute warm up, we did 3 rounds of 10 minutes worth exercise - an upper body pod, a lower body pod and a kettle bell pod. Exercises included things like renegade rows, commandos, lunges and sleds. After completing 1 round of exercises at a pod, we had to do a right corner run and then repeat the round until the 10 minutes was over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday, Day 3</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/wednesday-day-3/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and Lift (50min) classes just like Monday, except that Lift was focussed entirely on upper body exercises.
Speed involved 50 calorie sprints and then some rest equal to the time you took to complete the 50 calories. We were meant to do three lots of sprints but I could only burn 130 calories so I&amp;rsquo;m a bit annoyed. My legs are still shot from the Lift class on Monday.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuesday, Day 2</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/tuesday-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I had a kickboxing PT session (45min) with coach Darian at Prana. It&amp;rsquo;s hard work and sometimes I regret my life choices while I&amp;rsquo;m there, but once the session is over, I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I&amp;rsquo;ve done it. I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to these sessions for at least a year now, for at least two times a week and it&amp;rsquo;s really improved my fitness. I highly recommend you try kickboxing with Darian - he&amp;rsquo;s a hard task master but you&amp;rsquo;ll get a lot out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monday, Day 1</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/week-1/monday-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Training Today, I did the Speed (20min) and lower body Lift (50min)n classes at Prana. For those of you that don&amp;rsquo;t know, Speed is a cardio-based class with lots of bike work paired with either running or lifting medium weights. Lift is a strength-based class with a lot of heavy weights lifting.
Go back to Table of Contents
Food Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of what I ate today:
Breakfast: Overnight oats with peanut butter and mixed berries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pre Challenge Prep</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2023 08:23:37 +1030</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/posts/pre-challenge/pre-challenge-prep/</guid>
      <description>Fitness testing On Saturday, I went down to Grange Jetty to complete some fitness testing prior to the eight week challenge. The fitness testing included:
1 minute of push ups. 1 minute of sit ups. A beach run from Grange Jetty to Henley Jetty and back. I was a bit worried about the run, as my aerobic capacity is not the greatest. But I got through it in a time of 28:42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://greengypsy.github.io/my-eight-week-challenge/about/</guid>
      <description>Who am I? G&amp;rsquo;day folks! I&amp;rsquo;m Christina and I&amp;rsquo;m a business analyst by day, technical writer by night.
What is this blog about? I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to take part in Prana Athletica&amp;rsquo;s eight week challenge to improve my fitness and overall health. I also want to improve my understanding of how websites are created, given how fundamental it is to my jobs. So I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to create a website blog to keep myself accountable throughout the eight weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
